

 \times

ihar.yazerski@outlook.com

+375447513822

0

Minsk, Belarus

igorezersky.digital

in

linkedin.com/in/iharyazerski

(7)

github.com/igorezersky

SKILLS

RESTful API (wsgi/asgi)

Message Queuing

Swagger

Crawling

Docker

CI/CD

NIP

ML

Project management

LANGUAGES

English

Upper-Intermediate

Russian

Proficient

Belarusian

Proficient

INTERESTS

Traveling

Management

Football

Snowboarding

Ihar Yazerski

Senior Python Developer

I'm a Python developer and architect with a strong background in computer science and ML. Experienced in RESTful API design and development (*FastAPI, Flask, Starlette, Sanic, Django*), CI\CD (*Docker, Jenkins, Ansible*), Messaging (*RabbitMQ, Redis, Celery*), ML (*Pandas, Jupyter, Numpy, Gensim, spaCy, Scikit-Learn*) and Telegram bots.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Python Developer Globant

08/2021 - Present Minsk

A digitally native company that helps organizations reinvent themselves to create a way forward and unleash their potential

Activity

 Backend developer (microservices) on the financial valuation and modeling system by one of Big Four accounting organizations. Technical stack: REST API (Python, Sanic), messaging (Celery, RabbitMQ), CI/CD (Docker)

Data Scientist Silk Data

05/2018 - 08/2021 Minsk

Develops software products based on natural language processing and artificial intelligence, provides software development and deployment services

Activity

- Architect and project manager of the extension from Chrome Web Store for analysis and summarization of Google search results. Technical stack: REST API (Python, FastAPI), summarization (spaCy, own implementation of TextRank).
- Data Scientist and backend developer on the ML-based plagiarism system for one of the lead South African universities. Technical stack: REST API (Python, FastAPI), messaging (Celery, Redis, RabbitMQ), text analysis & comparison (spaCy, Gensim, Scikit-Learn), CI\CD (Docker).
- Data Scientist and backend developer on the legal contracts analysis system (clauses detection, referencing to laws, etc.). Technical stack: REST API (Python, FastAPI), classification (spaCy, Umap, Scikit-Learn), database (PostgreSQL), CI\CD (Docker, Jenkins, Ansible)
- Backend developer (microservices) on the ML-based semantic search system. Technical stack: REST API (Python, FastAPI), messaging (RabbitMQ), database (MySQL), index (Milvus), CI\CD (Docker, Jenkins, Ansible)

Data ScientistCIB Software

09/2017 - 05/2018 Minsk

Creation of software for standard word processing systems

Activity

- □ Engine developer on the multilingual OCR system. Technical stack: C++, Tesseract.
- Backend developer on the vacancies analysis system for HR specialists. Technical stack: REST API (Python, Flask), topic modeling & text comparison (spaCy, Gensim).

OPEN SOURCE

pydeployhelp

pydeployhelp is CLI tool that helps integrating deploy (via Docker) to Python projects

cookiecutter-api

cookiecutter-api is a cookiecutter template for web-service RESTful API on Python

EDUCATION

Information systems and technologies (Software Engineer)Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics

09/2015 - 07/2019 Minsk